# EXPERIENCED SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY EXECUTIVE

Bringing management of global software development teams, deep understanding of technology, technical operations experience, revenue generation, digital media market visions, and proven senior level management leadership skills to move a growing company to new levels of success.

Proven track record of managing teams developing back office, UX, and data delivery of the Global TV ratings business at Nielsen, the market leader in the \$80B television and radio advertising industry. Strong experience in outsourcing and business process optimization. Experience managing global teams developing applications, SDKs, and APIs in the Internet and mobile media space. Excellent people and interpersonal relationship skills. Led Nielsen's Florida Counsel responsible for community relations and involvement. Well respected change agent.

■ ■ Fully trained and certified Six Sigma executive black belt. ■ ■ ■

### AREAS OF EXPERTISE

Managing Global Software Development Teams | Strategic Planning | P&L Oversight | Product Development & Management SDLC | Business Process Analysis | Cross-Functional Team Leadership | Networking | SaaS | PaaS | IaaS Continuous Process Improvements | Strategic Partnerships | Partner & Vendor Management | Resource Allocation Budgeting | Negotiations | Customer Focus | Cloud Computing | Mobile Applications | Telecommunications Security | Agile | Kanban | Quality Assurance | Program & Project Management | Java | .NET | iOS | Android

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

SCENESAVE, LLC | Tampa, FL | 2018 - Present

### **Acting CTO/Advisor**

Acting CTO for a venture capital-based startup SceneSave. SceneSave is a shoppable mobile media platform created for people who love shows, characters, stories and scenes. Audio and voice recognition enabled, SceneSave brings audiences closer to shows by transforming scenes into "window displays", showcasing brands in the context of scene and converting viewers into consumers the moment inspiration strikes.

- Responsible for a team of off-shore full stack development engineers for delivery of the MVP to acquire funding.
- Specified end-to-end system architecture for user scalability and growth, from 2000 MVP users to 1M+ at product rollout.
- Product includes voice recognition and automatic content recognition in a simple to use android and iOS second screen application.
- Interface with brand owners, broadcast networks, and ad agencies to monetize the service. The application employs targeted advertising based upon machine learning determination of users' preferences.
- Extensive use of AWS S3, EC2, AMI, and Elastic Load Balancing.
- Tools include Spring Boot, Micro Services, Hybrid (React + Native), Angular 5, OpenID Connect, IntelliJ IDEA, Eclipse, Java, Xcode, Full Stack Firebase, Custom/AWS API Management, PostgreSQL, IntelliJ IDEA, Eclipse, Jenkins, SQL, TensorFlow, Caffe2, and Apache MXNet
- Developed companies' 2-year product roadmap including technology, strategy, and intellectual property.
- Developed architecture on logical functional modules, including UX, Measurement, AI/ML, MarTech, CMS, SDK for white labeling, Ad serving, privacy/GDRP, and location-based services.
- Responsible for presenting to VC and investment firms for securing funding.

# COPPERLINE MEDIA. LLC | Tampa, FL | 2016 - Present

## **President and CEO**

Specialize in digital media streaming technologies and platforms for over-the-top and mobile applications, engineering and product development, global marketing strategies, and global sales strategies in the radio and TV industry

Developed cloud architecture for Viacom and ABC/Disney to seamlessly be able to use any cloud services provider.

- Completed technology selection for an open standard for audio watermarking for SMPTE.
- Developed a go to market strategy for a global digital media marketing company.
- Developed a machine learning at AI system using large disparate data feeds to proactively identify problems and issues with large amounts of audience, broadcast, and STB data.
- Advised a collection of companies as to how to protect their IP and develop a licensing strategy.
- Oversee and manage software development, test, and delivery of highly visible and strategic company initiatives.

# THE NIELSEN COMPANY | Oldsmar, FL | 2000 - 2016

# Senior Vice President of Engineering - Global Business Services

Managed a global development group in excess of 200 people with more than a \$20 million budget for all of Nielsen technology worldwide, including hardware and software platforms. Hands on and involved management style.

- Responsible for a software development team that developed television and mobile device synchronization applications. The system included use of cloud-based content management systems for delivery of interactive information to consumers' mobile devices during television programs, triggered by signals in the audio of the program.
- Designed and deployed 140,000 in-home Linux and Java based measurement devices. Each device was networked back to the central office.
- Lead development, management and operations of big data used for operational intelligence to measure application and platform performance. Established and communicated business intelligence KPIs both internally and externally as a measure of success. Successfully lead business process optimization through strong offshore relationships.
- Managed developers to design solutions for TV and radio audience measurement. This included hardware, firmware, and software development using Linux, Java, and C#. Conducted and approved design and code reviews.
- Accountable for IT infrastructure operations and infrastructure refresh with a strong focus on operational cost reduction. Strong experience with brick and mortar, virtual, and hybrid data center upgrades and technology.
- Responsible for managing teams for the development of mobile application SDKs and APIs, and their cloud-based distribution through SaaS, IaaS, and PaaS.
- Frequent speaker at community and industry events.
- Mentor for junior level employees. Established employee resource groups as a means of employee networking and problem solving.
- Responsible for budgeting and P&L as it affected national and local television markets through close alignment with sales and marketing.
- Group obtained the highest employee satisfaction survey rating nationwide.

#### **Vice President of Research and Development**

Led a team of senior researchers developing new innovative methods of measuring new forms of media. Research topics
included passive face recognition systems, audio and video watermarking technologies, audio and video signature
technologies, active tagging of Internet content and mobile devices. Responsible for all consumer electronics industry
measurement innovations.

# VELA RESEARCH, LP | Clearwater, FL | 1993 - 2000

# Vice President and General Manager of Asia Pacific Rim Division

Reported directly to the President and led up to 100 reports across multiple global locations while maintaining full accountability for P&L.

- Boosted sales from 5% to 20% of overall revenues by initiating specification and localization of products for Asia, establishment of sales and distribution channels, and creating support and service mechanisms for the region.
- Drove new product development, identification of new product market opportunities, maintenance of existing products, direct leadership of project and product managers, and preservation of company intellectual property.
- Negotiated partner and vendor contracts and managed technical sales support groups.
- Served as the face of the company for all technical marketing functions including press interviews, speaking engagements and seminars, and writing articles for various industry trade journals.
- Contributing member of various technical standards bodies relating to the Cable and Broadcast industry and digital media including SCTE, SMPTE, MPEG, PCI, and the DVD forum.

## **Vice President of Operations**

Promoted to Vice President Operations in 1997, as product families matured and more products were available, which also allowed me to manage not only all Product Development and Product Management activities, but also Manufacturing, IS and IT, Technical Services, and Customer Service operations.

### **Vice President of Technical Research**

Developed video compression products based upon MPEG-2 technologies. Delivered many successful products to the cable and broadcast industry, including one of the world's first MPEG-2 storage encoders, the first MPEG-2 decoder to be used for cable ad insertion, and an MPEG-2 based video server system used for video-on-demand.

Early Career History

HOME SHOPPING NETWORK **Software Project Leader** 

SKYDATA, INC.

Senior Member, Technical Staff

HARRIS CORPORATION

Software Project Leader, Senior Engineer

### PATENTS & PUBLICATIONS

- Frequent speaker at industry conferences on television, digital, and mobile technologies.
- Holder of 28 US and International patents.
- Awarded two technology Emmys from the National Academy of Television Arts and Sciences.

### **EDUCATION**

**ROLLINS COLLEGE - Bachelor of Science: Computer Science** 

EXECUTIVE LEADERSHIP TRAINING – Certificate: Ashridge London, England

EXECUTIVE LEADERSHIP TRAINING - Certificate: Duke University